Guide to the Wells Fargo Steinbeck Collection, 1892-1981
Department of Special Collections
- Series 11. Steinbeck and Hamilton Family Photographs, 1870s-1981
  - "Pupils' Recital | at | Odd Fellows Hall | Given by | Miss Ora E. Lauritzen, B. M. | Saturday, May 10, 1902. | 2 P.M.": printed announcement 1902 May 2 (Box 8, Othertype 54)
  - Class photograph of Esther Steinbeck. Written on verso: "Esther (right of blue collar)." n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 55)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 18 x 13 cm.
  - Esther and Beth Steinbeck. Salinas, CA: Butler n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 56)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 10 x 14 cm.
  - "Beth [Steinbeck], Uncle Will [Hamilton], and Mr. Cutting, the minister." n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 57)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 5 x 6 cm.
  - Esther Steinbeck holding flowers in a white dress and a white straw hat was given to her by D. P. Trask n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 58)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 13 x 18 cm.
  - Esther, Beth, baby John Steinbeck, and a cousin seated with pillows on the steps of the Central Avenue House in Salinas, Calif. n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 59)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 9 x 6 cm.
  - Six-month-old John Steinbeck seated in a stroller in front of the Salinas house. n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 60)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 6 cm.
  - Six-month-old John Steinbeck seated in a stroller in front of the Salinas house. n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 61)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 6 cm.
  - John Steinbeck on a stool in front of the Salinas house. n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 62)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 6 x 9 cm.
  - Fourteen children posing in a garden setting. John Steinbeck at lower left n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 63)
    - 1 photographic postcard: b. & w.; 14 x 9 cm.
  - John Steinbeck in front of the Salinas house n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 64)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 12 x 16 cm.
  - Jean and Gussie Hamilton n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 65)
    - 1 photographic postcard: b. & w.; 9 x 14 cm.
  - Beth, Olive, and Esther Steinbeck n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 66)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 9 x 9 cm.
  - Esther Steinbeck n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 67)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 9 x 9 cm.
  - John Steinbeck and a dog seated in a donkey cart with Mary Steinbeck astride the donkey n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 68)
    - 1 photographic postcard: b. & w.; 9 x 14 cm.
  - Beth Steinbeck n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 69)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 9 x 9 cm.
  - John Steinbeck in the front yard of the Salinas house n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 70)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 9 x 9 cm.
  - Portrait of John Steinbeck. Written on verso: "June 1919, 17 years 4 months." n.p.: Green's Studio. 1919 June (Box 8, Othertype 71)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 10 x 15 cm.
  - John Steinbeck and Esther Steinbeck, Watsonville, Calif. 1919. 1919 (Box 8, Othertype 72)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 12 x 17 cm.
  - Esther Steinbeck astride a horse. Written on verso: "Esther and Doxology (the last hymne.)" n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 73)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 14 x 9 cm.
  - Esther Steinbeck, Will Martin, and Beth Steinbeck seated on the running board of an automobile n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 74)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 8 cm.
  - Will Martin, Esther Steinbeck, and Beth Steinbeck posed next to an automobile n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 75)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 8 cm.
  - Olive and John Ernst Steinbeck at home--beneath the mistletoe n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 76)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 14 cm.
  - Olive Hamilton Steinbeck in a rocking chair on the porch n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 77)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 9 cm.
  - Olive, John Steinbeck, Mary, and John Ernst Steinbeck seated around the Christmas tree n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 78)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 15 x 10 cm.
  - Esther and John Ernst Steinbeck seated on the steps of the Salinas house n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 79)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 8 cm.
  - John Steinbeck with a dog n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 80)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 9 x 15 cm.
  - John Steinbeck in a hat and coat, sitting on the porch steps of the Salinas house playing with a dog n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 81)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 14 x 9cm.
  - Esther Steinbeck n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 82)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 7 x 10 cm.
  - Esther Steinbeck n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 83)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 11 x 15 cm.
  - Esther Steinbeck, Mills College graduate n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 84)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 10 cm.
  - Esther Steinbeck n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 85)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 10 x 14 cm.
  - Esther Steinbeck n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 86)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 9 x 15 cm.
  - Newspaper clipping. Redding, CA: Redding (Calif.) Record Searchlight n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 87)
  - Esther Steinbeck, Shasta County ca. 1920s (Box 8, Othertype 88)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 14 cm.
  - Esther Steinbeck n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 89)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 14 x 8 cm.
  - Esther Steinbeck seated in her Agricultural Extension Service car n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 90)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 14 x 8 cm.
  - Carrol James Rodgers on his wedding day, in the garden of the Steinbeck home, Salinas, Calif. 1924 May 11 (Box 8, Othertype 91)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 7 x 11 cm.
  - Wedding announcement: "Mr. and Mrs. John Ernst Steinbeck |announce the marriage of their daughter | Olive Esther | to | Mr. Carrol James Rodgers | on Sunday, the eleventh of May | one thousand nine hundred and twenty-four | Salinas, California" 1924 May 11 (Box 8, Othertype 92)
  - Esther Steinbeck Rodgers in her wedding dress. (1924). 1924 (Box 8, Othertype 93)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 7 x 11 cm.
  - Esther Steinbeck Rodgers and her maid of honor, Mary Steinbeck 1924 (Box 8, Othertype 94)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 7 x 11 cm.
  - Carrol Rodgers and Esther Steinbeck Rodgers on their wedding day 1924 (Box 8, Othertype 95)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 7 x 11 cm.
  - Best man Marion Rodgers and maid of honor Mary Steinbeck 1924 (Box 8, Othertype 96)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 7 x 11 cm.
  - Mary Steinbeck Dekker, Esther Steinbeck Rodgers, and Beth Steinbeck Ainsworth n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 97)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 7 x 11 cm.
  - Esther, Carrol, and Carolee Rodgers; Beth Steinbeck Ainsworth; Olive Hamilton Steinbeck; Mary and Bill Dekker; (John) Ernst Steinbeck; and Gene and Bob Ainsworth at the Rodgers house in Watsonville, Calif. n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 98)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 14 x 8 cm.
  - Esther Steinbeck Rodgers holding Carolee Rodgers. n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 99)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 14 cm.
  - John Ernst Steinbeck holding Bob Ainsworth and Carolee Rodgers. n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 100)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 14 cm.
  - Olive Hamilton Steinbeck holding Bob Ainsworth n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 101)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 14 cm.
  - Olive and John Ernst Steinbeck with seven grandchildren n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 102)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 10 x 6 cm.
  - John Ernst with Bob Ainsworth, baby Joan Dekker, and Carolee Rodgers n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 103)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 6 x 10 cm.
  - Olive Hamilton Steinbeck. n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 104)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 6 x 10 cm.
  - John Ernst and Olive Hamilton Steinbeck with Joan Dekker, Bob Ainsworth, and Carolee Rodgers. n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 105)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 6 x 10 cm.
  - John Ernst Steinbeck at the Rodgers house, Watsonville, Calif. n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 106)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 7 x 12 cm.
  - John Ernst Steinbeck n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 107)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 9 cm. diameter
  - John Ernst Steinbeck at the Rodgers house, Watsonville, Calif. n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 108)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 10 x 14 cm.
  - Olive Hamilton Steinbeck n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 109)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 13 x 18 cm.
  - Esther Rodgers with Carolee, Mary, and baby Florence n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 110)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 18 x 28 cm.
  - John Ernst Steinbeck in front of the Pacific Grove, Calif., cottage n.d. (Box 8, Othertype 111)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 18 x 26 cm.
  - Portrait of John Steinbeck, signed "Tunnicliffe SF." 1932 (Box 8, Othertype 112)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 20 x 25 cm.
  - Portrait of John Steinbeck by Sonja Noskowiak, Carmel Volume II (1930s-1981) (Box 9, Othertype 1)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 9 x 11 cm.
  - Portrait of John Steinbeck by Joseph Breitenbach 1947 (Box 9, Othertype 2)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 20 x 25 cm.
  - Sheep dog Willie, Beth Steinbeck Ainsworth, John Steinbeck, Mary Steinbeck Dekker, and Thom Steinbeck. n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 3)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 11 x 7 cm.
  - Willie (dog), Bob Ainsworth, Carolee Rodgers, Liz Ainsworth, and Jean Ainsworth. n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 4)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 11 x 7 cm.
  - John Steinbeck and Gwyn Steinbeck. n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 5)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 9 x 15 cm.
  - John Steinbeck holding baby Thom in a christening gown, with a nurse on the steps of a church. n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 6)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 14 cm.
  - Steinbeck cousins and their spouses in the driveway of the Rodgers house, Watsonville, Calif.: Liz Ainsworth, Mary Rodgers, Carolee Rodgers Finney, Bob Finney, Sue Dekker Blois, Dick Blois, Florence Rodgers Dethlefsen, and Ed Dethlefsen n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 7)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 11 x 7 cm.
  - Anita Dormody, Esther Steinbeck Rodgers, Joan Dekker Heyler, John Steinbeck n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 8)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 5 cm.
  - Anita Dormody, Esther Steinbeck Rodgers, John Steinbeck, Joan Dekker Heyler. n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 9)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 5 cm.
  - Thom Steinbeck sitting in a birdbath n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 10)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 20 x 25 cm.
  - Gwyn and Thom Steinbeck 1946 (Box 9, Othertype 11)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 7 x 12 cm.
  - Gwyn and Thom Steinbeck 1946 (Box 9, Othertype 12)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 7 x 12 cm.
  - Gwyn and Thom Steinbeck 1946 (Box 9, Othertype 13)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 16 x 20 cm.
  - Gwyn and Thom Steinbeck 1946 (Box 9, Othertype 14)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 7 x 12 cm.
  - Thom Steinbeck 1946 (Box 9, Othertype 15)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 7 x 12 cm.
  - Thom Steinbeck 1946 (Box 9, Othertype 16)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 17 x 12 cm.
  - John Steinbeck IV. n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 17)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 11 x 6 cm.
  - John Steinbeck IV. n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 18)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 11 x 6 cm.
  - Nurse holding John Steinbeck IV n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 19)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 11 x 6 cm.
  - Thom Steinbeck n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 20)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 14 x 19 cm.
  - Thom Steinbeck n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 21)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 14 x 19 cm.
  - Thom Steinbeck and John Steinbeck IV n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 22)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 19 x 15 cm.
  - Gwyn and John Steinbeck IV, 18 days old. n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 23)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 9 x 9 cm.
  - Nurse, John Steinbeck IV, and Willie (dog). n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 24)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 9 x 9 cm.
  - John Steinbeck IV and Thom Steinbeck n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 25)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 24 x 19 cm.
  - John Steinbeck IV n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 26)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 19 x 24 cm.
  - Thom Steinbeck n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 27)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 11 x 15 cm.
  - John Steinbeck seated, with a cane n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 28)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 12 x 16 cm.
  - John Steinbeck in a tuxedo n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 29)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 10 x 15 cm.
  - Elaine Scott and John Steinbeck n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 30)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 12 x 8 cm.
  - John Steinbeck IV and Thom Steinbeck 1950 Summer (Box 9, Othertype 31)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 10 cm.
  - Elaine Scott with John Steinbeck IV and Thom Steinbeck at the beach n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 32)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 12 x 8 cm.
  - John Steinbeck with Thom Steinbeck and John Steinbeck IV n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 33)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 12 x 8 cm.
  - Thom Steinbeck and John Steinbeck IV in suits, with false mustaches and cigars n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 34)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 8 cm.
  - Thom Steinbeck and John Steinbeck IV at the beach. n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 35)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 12 x 8 cm.
  - John Steinbeck in living room n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 36)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 10 x 8 cm.
  - John Steinbeck and two men in military uniform n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 37)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 6 x 5 cm.
  - John Steinbeck n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 38)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 10 x 8 cm.
  - Portrait of John Steinbeck n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 39)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 21 x 26 cm.
  - Elaine Steinbeck and John Steinbeck wedding picture 1950 Dec. 28 (Box 9, Othertype 40)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 19 x 24 cm.
  - John Steinbeck and Carolee Rodgers n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 41)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 10 x 8 cm.
  - Elaine Steinbeck and John Steinbeck n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 42)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 10 x 8 cm.
  - John Steinbeck, Elaine Steinbeck, and Mrs. Anderson (Elaine's mother) n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 43)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 10 x 8 cm.
  - Waverly Scott [Elaine Rodger's daughter] and Mrs. Anderson n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 44)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 10 x 8 cm.
  - Beth Steinbeck Ainsworth, Mary Steinbeck Dekker, Esther and Carrol Rodgers at Carolee's wedding 1952 (Box 9, Othertype 45)
    - 1 photograph: col.; 6 x 8 cm.
  - Carolee Rodgers Finney pinning a corsage on Beth Steinbeck Ainsworth n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 46)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 26 x 21 cm.
  - Elaine Steinbeck, Terrence McNally, John Steinbeck, John Steinbeck IV, and Thom Steinbeck on board the S.S. Rotterdam, Holland-America Line n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 47)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 12 x 17 cm.
  - Elaine Steinbeck and John Steinbeck dancing aboard Mn. Saturnia 1962 June (Box 9, Othertype 48)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 17 x 12 cm.
  - John Steinbeck IV, Elaine Steinbeck, Terrence McNally, John Steinbeck, and Thom Steinbeck at an outdoor dinner. Mykonos, Greece 1962 (Box 9, Othertype 49)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 18 x 13 cm.
  - John Steinbeck standing in a street cafe. Mykonos, Greece 1962 (Box 9, Othertype 50)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 13 x 18 cm.
  - John Steinbeck and a pelican. Mykonos, Greece 1962 (Box 9, Othertype 51)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 13 x 18 cm.
  - John Steinbeck with cigarette, leaning against a tree n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 52)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 25 x 20 cm.
  - Display of the Nobel medals n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 53)
    - 1 photograph: col.; 9 x 9 cm.
  - John Steinbeck's last Thanksgiving with the family in California--at the Rodgers house in Watsonville. John Steinbeck carving turkey as sister Beth supervises. Joan Dekker Heyler looks on. n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 54)
    - 1 photograph: col.; 9 x 9 cm.
  - David Heyler, Mary Steinbeck Dekker, and Esther Steinbeck Rodgers n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 55)
    - 1 photograph: col.; 9 x 9 cm.
  - Joan Dekker Heyler n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 56)
    - 1 photograph: col.; 9 x 9 cm.
  - Beth Steinbeck Ainsworth in the garden of the Pacific Grove, Calif., cottage. n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 57)
    - 1 photograph: col.; 8 x 12 cm.
  - John Steinbeck IV and John Steinbeck at Sag Harbor, NY n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 58)
    - 1 photograph: col.; 12 x 8 cm.
  - John Steinbeck and John Steinbeck IV at Sag Harbor, NY n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 59)
    - 1 photograph: col.; 12 x 8 cm.
  - John Steinbeck IV in military uniform on a pier, holding a fishing pole n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 60)
    - 1 photograph: col.; 8 x 12 cm.
  - John Steinbeck and John Steinbeck IV at Sag Harbor, NY n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 61)
    - 1 photograph: col.; 8 x 12 cm.
  - John Steinbeck IV at Sag Harbor, NY n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 62)
    - 1 photograph: col.; 8 x 12 cm.
  - John Steinbeck and Elaine Steinbeck with a view of the house in the distance. Sag Harbor, NY 1958 (Box 9, Othertype 63)
    - 1 photograph: col.; 12 x 8 cm.
  - "Joyous Garde." Sag Harbor, NY n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 64)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 10 cm.
  - Steinbeck swimming pool and the house beyond. Sag Harbor, NY n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 65)
    - 1 photograph: col.; 10 x 8 cm.
  - John Steinbeck IV and John Steinbeck fishing. n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 66)
    - 1 photograph: col.; 12 x 8 cm.
  - Steinbeck house, view from the pier. Sag Harbor, NY n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 67)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 8 x 8 cm.
  - John Steinbeck IV and John Steinbeck fishing n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 68)
    - 1 photograph: col.; 12 x 8 cm.
  - "John on the firing range Dec '66.": Three pictures of John Steinbeck 1966 Dec. (Box 9, Othertype 69)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 7 x 19 cm.
  - "John in the Delta--Vietnam Jan '67." 1967 Jan. (Box 9, Othertype 70)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 18 x 13 cm.
  - "John in the Delta, Vietnam January 1967. In rice paddies--look at the mud!" 1967 Jan. (Box 9, Othertype 71)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 18 x 13 cm.
  - "Thom [Steinbeck] at Ford Ord." n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 72)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 9 x 6 cm.
  - John Steinbeck. Written on verso: "John in fatigues borrowed from an Army chaplain in Hue. The troops called him 'Father.'" n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 73)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 9 x 6 cm.
  - "Johnny [Steinbeck IV] in Saigon Christmas '66." 1966 Dec. (Box 9, Othertype 74)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 9 x 6 cm.
  - Friend and John Steinbeck IV. n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 75)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 9 x 7 cm.
  - John Steinbeck IV in Army uniform. n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 76)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 7 x 9 cm.
  - John Steinbeck IV in Army uniform. n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 77)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 9 x 7 cm.
  - "John [Steinbeck] & Prince Bhann," Thailand 1967 (Box 9, Othertype 78)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 14 x 9 cm.
  - "John on the floor at Baan Thai. The Princess with her back to the camera & one of their nieces." Thailand. 1967 (Box 9, Othertype 79)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 14 x 9 cm.
  - "Our table at Baan Thai." Thailand. (1967). 1967 (Box 9, Othertype 80)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 14 x 9 cm.
  - "John at Villa Flora," Thailand 1967 (Box 9, Othertype 81)
    - 1 photograph: col.; 12 x 8 cm.
  - John Steinbeck, Thanksgiving Day. New York. 1968 Nov. (Box 9, Othertype 82)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 23 x 17 cm.
  - Windmill, Sag Harbor, NY [The John Steinbeck Memorial plaque is on the face of the building by the flag pole] n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 83)
    - 1 photograph: col.; 8 x 8 cm.
  - The John Steinbeck Memorial plaque on the Sag Harbor windmill n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 84)
    - 1 photograph: col.; 8 x 8 cm.
  - Close-up of the John Steinbeck Old Whalers Festival Memorial plaque: "The Old Whalers Festival, Inc. of Sag Harbor dedicates this plaque to the memory of John Steinbeck, noted author, Nobel and Pulitzer Prize winner, who gave so willingly of his time and great talent as Honorary Chairman of the Old Whalers Festival, Sag Harbor 1963-1966." n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 85)
    - 1 photograph: col.; 8 x 8 cm.
  - Sketch of John Steinbeck superimposed over Cannery Row, by Lauren Dethlefsen (Bailard), granddaughter of Esther Steinbeck Rodgers and great-niece of Jon Steinbeck 1978 (Box 9, Othertype 86)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 12 x 16 cm.
  - . Beth Steinbeck Ainsworth and Elaine Steinbeck, with eight Steinbeck House members n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 87)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 19 x 24 cm.
  - Press release describing Steinbeck House n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 88)
  - Six Steinbeck House members on the front steps n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 89)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 24 x 19 cm.
  - Press release describing the John Steinbeck Library, Salinas, Calif. n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 90)
  - The John Steinbeck Library, with two boys viewing a statue of John Steinbeck n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 91)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 24 x 19 cm.
  - Press release describing Steinbeck country n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 92)
  - View of the countryside with fenced pastures. Steinbeck country. n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 93)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 24 x 19 cm.
  - Esther Steinbeck Rodgers and Katherine Rodgers Ashcraft seated in an automobile at Esther's Mills College Reunion n.d. (Box 9, Othertype 94)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 20 x 25 cm.
  - "Mills College 50 year reunion June 1964" [Esther Steinbeck Rodgers third from left.] 1964 June (Box 9, Othertype 95)
    - 1 photograph: b. & w.; 25 x 20 cm.
  - Steinbeck Family Reunion 1981 June 27 (Box 9, Othertype 96)
    - 1 photograph: col.; 25 x 20 cm.
  - Steinbeck Family Reunion 1981 June 27 (Box 9, Othertype 97)
    - 1 photograph: col.; 25 x 20 cm.
  - Steinbeck Family Reunion 1981 June 27 (Box 9, Othertype 98)
    - 1 photograph: col.; 25 x 20 cm.
- Series 12. John Steinbeck Books and Articles
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Cup of gold: a life of Henry Morgan, buccaneer, with occasional reference to history. New York: Robert M. McBride & Company, 1929. viii, 269 p., 20 cm., Wanting dust jacket. References: First edition. Johnson, AFE, 4th ed., p. 472; Goldstone, A1a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Cup of gold: a life of Henry Morgan, buccaneer, with occasional reference to history. New York: Robert M. McBride & Company, 1929. viii, 269 p., 20 cm., Bound in yellow cloth; stamped in black. Signed by Helen W. Proda on front free endpaper. Wanting flamboyant piratical dust jacket. References: First edition. Johnson, AFE, 4th ed., p. 472; Goldstone, A1a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Cup of gold: a life of Sir Henry Morgan, buccaneer, with occasional reference to history / by John Steinbeck; preface by Lewis Gannett. New York: Covici-Friede, c1936. viii, 269 p.; 20 cm., Inscribed on front paste-down: "Again for Esther | John Steinbeck" Dark maroon cloth, with dust jacket. First edition, second issue. Goldstone, A1b.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The Pastures of Heaven / by John Steinbeck. New York: Brewer, Warren & Putnam, 1932. [8], 294 p. 20cm., First edition, first issue. Signed by Esther Rodgers on recto of front free endpaper. Tipped-in (now removed), "The Neatest Trick of the Year," n.d., an advertisement for the Ballou edition of The Pastures of Heaven. 4 pp. (1 folded leaf). References: Goldstone A2a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Nothing so monstrous: a story / by John Steinbeck. [New York, The Pynson Printers] 1936. 30, [2] p. illus. 24 cm., Acknowledgment: "This is the first separate publication of Nothing So Monstrous, which originally formed one of the episodes in The Pastures Of Heaven, published by Brewer, Warren & Putnam in 1932. The epilogue was written specially for this book. December, 1936" Colophon: "This copy of Nothing So Monstrous with pen and ink drawings by Donald McKay was made by the Pynson Printers of New York at the request of John Steinbeck for presentation to [in manuscript] Esther and Carrol with love | John Steinbeck" Marbled boards, orange buckram spine. Original glassine chipped. Goldstone, A2f. [note: Goldstone does not list any presentation copies printed "at the request of John Steinbeck."]
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. To a god unknown / by John Steinbeck. New York: Robert O. Ballou, c1933. [8], 325 p. 20 cm., First edition. First issue. Goldstone, A3a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. To a god unknown / by John Steinbeck. New York: Robert O. Ballou, c1933. [8], 325 p. 20 cm., First edition, first issue. Inscribed on verso of blank preceding half-title: "For Esther & Caroll | from | John" Goldstone, A3a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. To a god unknown / by John Steinbeck. New York: Robert O. Ballou, c1933. [8], 325 p. 20 cm., Second issue in dust jacket. Dust jacket pasted to front and rear paste-downs. Goldstone, A3a.